icollector.com 2000-09-30

# icollector.com: the marketplace & resource for experts in arts, antiques & collectibles

| 

When you visit a Website displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, you can expect to be notified of: What personally identifiable information of yours is collected; What organization is collecting the information; How the information is used; With whom the information may be shared; What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information; What kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under the company's control; and How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to Carol Gardey, Client Services Director by email at [customer.services@icollector.com](mailto:customer.services@icollector.com?subject=TRUSTe_Statement) or mail at icollector, United House, 9 Pembridge Road, London W11 3JY, UK. If the Website has not responded to your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, please contact [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/users/watchdog.html).

In the ongoing operation of our icollector website, Interactive Collector Ltd. (IC) collects and, in some cases, discloses information about our Users. This Privacy Policy describes where and what we collect and how we use your information. Moreover, some of your personally identifiable information is disclosed to and may be used by third parties. 

****

**Where does icollector collect information?**

We collect information from many areas on icollector. These include when you register with icollector in order to participate in our services such as: Online Auctions, Auction Catalogs presale bidding, the Community and My Agent; submit a form or e-mail requesting information from one of the listed dealers, galleries, auction houses, publications or fairs; and whenever you subscribe to our Newsletter, enter a competition, complete a questionnaire, leave comments in the Feedback, Community or Contact sections which are available throughout the icollector site. 

**

What information does icollector collect?

**

The type of personal information we may gather among the different areas of icollector includes the following: your name, contact name, billing address, shipping address, phone number, fax number, e-mail address, relevant password, User ID, credit card information, comments and personal messages in our Community and Feedback areas and personal correspondence such as e-mails or letters.

We also automatically track certain information about you just in the course of using our site. This information includes the URL that you just came from and the URL you   go to next, the browser you are using and your IP address. This information is gathered for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. It is common practice for most websites to collect this information automatically. 

As part of providing our services, icollector uses cookies to store and sometimes track information about you. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. icollector uses cookies with regards to the following areas: Online Auctions, Registration, and the Art Price Guide. 

**

How does icollector use your information?

**

In areas that require you to submit personal information such as our registration form, this is to allow you to participate in certain offerings such as Online Auctions, Auction Catalogs' presale bidding, the Community, My Agent, Competitions and to receive our Newsletter. 

Cookies are used to measure certain traffic patterns, such as which area of icollector you have visited, and your visiting patterns in the aggregate. 

Your information is important for IC to analyze for internal purposes as it helps us to improve our site by tailoring it to meet your needs. More specifically, IC may use your information to analyze site usage, to help in developing our marketing and public relations, and to improve the site's content, commercial offerings, layout and usability. 

**

What choice do you have with regards to collection, use and distribution of your information?

**

You have the ability to opt out of use of certain information that you provide to icollector. For example, if you choose to disenable your cookies you may still visit all areas of icollector and continue to participate in Online Auctions and the Community. 

**

Who does icollector disclose your information to?

**

We do not sell or rent any personally identifiable information about our users to any third party. For the purpose of advertising, visitor and user information is aggregated for reporting to advertisers and prospective partners. However, in these situations, we never disclose to these entities any information that could be used to personally identify you, such as your name, address, User ID, password, and credit card number.

****

**IC only discloses personal information in limited circumstances as outlined in the following sections:**

**Online Auctions**  
We have designed Online Auctions so that no personal identifying information is displayed online or is accessible to the general public. In Online Auctions, other users can see your User ID and your bids but not your e-mail address. 

The only time any personal identifiable information is released is if you are a successful bidder in one of our Online Auctions whereby the Seller will be sent an e-mail containing the winning bidder's User ID, e-mail address, phone number, and home address. Your credit card number is not released. 

We never disclose your password and you may not disclose your password to any third parties or share it with any third parties without risking compromise of your User identity.

**Auctions Catalogs presale bidding**  
We have designed Auction Catalogs presale bidding so that no personal identifying information is displayed online or is accessible to the general public. In Auction Catalogs presale bidding, your bids are not disclosed as it is a 'closed bidding' system. 

The only time any personal identifiable information is released is when you submit a preale bid on an item in an Auction Catalog. In this case, the auction house will be sent a fax or an email containing your name, address, day and evening phone numbers, e-mail address, bid amount and lot number of the item you bid on. Your credit card number is not released. 

We never disclose your password and you may not disclose your password to any third parties or share it with any third parties without risking compromise of your User identity.

**Community**  
Only your Username is revealed in the Community. You have the option to reveal your email address when posting a message in a Forum if you would like someone to respond to you directly, however, icollector does not advise you to do so. 

**Galleries, Dealers, Publications, Exhibitions, Etc.**  
When you request information from one of our listed dealers, galleries, auction houses, publications, exhibitions, and fairs, only the contact information you specify is forwarded such as your name, address, phone, fax, and e-mail. 

**Disclaimer:**  
Excepting the areas listed above, icollector will only disclose your personal details if so required by law. 

**When and how does icollector contact Users?**

We will contact you by email (and in rare circumstances by phone or fax) in the following circumstances: (1) To confirm your registration on our site, (2) to confirm any bids you place, (3) if you are the winning bidder of a lot in Online Auctions or Auction Catalogs (4) if you are the winner of a competition on icollector, (5) if a problem arises with your account, (6) we may contact you from time to time to ask for specific feedback on the site, and (7) in response to a direct enquiry or suggestion from you.

IC may use your e-mail address and, where applicable, your mailing address, to contact you regarding administrative notices from time to time.

**

What is icollector's policy on Direct Mailings?

**

We will use your information for a direct mailing, such as our Newsletter, only if you expressly give us prior permission, which will be indicated to you. If you decide you no longer want to receive such mailings, you can remove yourself by sending an e-mail to the indicated address as provided. 

**Where can you change or update your information on the site?**

Registered Users may change their information in the following instances:

If you need to change your password for any reason, please go to [Forgotten Password](http://auction.icollector.com/os/send_password.shtml). If you need to update or change your registration information, please send a request to [customer.services@icollector.com](mailto:customer.services@icollector.com?subject=Changes_To_Registration_Information)

**

icollector Security

**

Security is of upmost importance to icollector. In order to demonstrate our commitment to security of your personal information we strictly limit access to any information of a private or personal nature received in the company through use of passwords and Usernames. 

Your Registration Information is password-protected so that only you have access to this personal information. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. We will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email. 

IP addresses are not linked to any personally identified information.

Please note that we use credit card information only to verify your account when you register with icollector. It is sent over our secure server using SSL Technology, an industry-wide encryption software. 

**

How can you be responsible for your information?

**

This privacy policy only covers IC's use and disclosure of information that IC collects from you. Please be aware, IC clients and third-party Internet sites accessible through IC's icollector have independent privacy and data collection practices. IC's icollector has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies or actions. Moreover, any personal information disclosed online between users in areas such as communities, e-mail, and forums, can be collected and used by others. Be aware, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. 

We welcome your questions regarding this privacy statement. Please submit any comments or inquiries to our [**Contact Us**](http://www.icollector.com/live/services/contact.htm) section.
